Luka Licheli

San Diego, CA 92105 (732) 586-4369 lukalicheli@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/lukalicheli lukalicheli.github.io/portfolio

I am a Full Stack Web Developer that is collaborative, but also a strong, independent, problem solver. Having used React paired with Material-UI Library, I have experience developing an intuitive user interface. I utilized reusable components and virtual DOM to give the app a mobile feel and used MongoDB and GraphQL to give it extensive functionality. Documentation is my best friend, along with having relentless tenacity with debugging errors in order to create a smooth performing and robust application.

Work History

Massage Envy *2017-2021*

- Making recommendations as to feasibility of implementation of modified or new technologies.
- Experience working with and managing customers.
- Adhered to project schedules and effectively reported the progress made to meet challenging deadlines.

La Pensione Hotel 2016-2017

- Maintaining and applying strong understanding of business practices to effectively fulfill responsibilities while working on multiple high-priority tasks.
- Assisted with troubleshooting and enhancement of the existing Web, Video and Mobile web applications and services.
- Serving as a technical expert in the evaluation and testing of the capabilities, characteristics and requirements of existing and emerging information systems technologies.

Education

San Diego City College 2017-2021

Associates Degree, Business Administration

San Diego, CA

San Diego, CA

UC San Diego Extension 2021-2022

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

3 /

Projects

Happy Hour

- A mobile app that lets users search for happy hour deals by zip code with an ability to add and delete reviews provided you are logged in.
- **Tools:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MUI Library, Apollo, MongoDB, Mongoose, NodeJs, Express, JWT Authentication, GraphQL
- Applied knowledge of mobile-first and responsive design principles using front-end frameworks and grid systems.
- Wrote unit tests & reviewed code prior to merging.
- Assisted with developing custom modules and plugins.
- Worked on infrastructure backlog tasks as assigned.

Note Taker

- Note Taker is an app that allows users to save notes online and stores it to local storage for the ability to use it offline.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, NodeJS, Express, Uniqid
- Involved in all aspects of the application development lifecycle: Idea, Development, QA,
 Documentation, Implementation, and Integration
- Optimized web applications to maximize speed and scale.

Technical Skills

- Javascript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3 (Flexbox, CSS Grid)
- React, MySQL, MongoDB
- NodeJS, NPM, Express, GraphQL
- jQuery, RESTful APIs, Axios
- MVC, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Design Patterns
- Bootstrap, MUI Library, Handlebars
- Mongoose, Sequelize, Insomnia, Apollo Sandbox
- Workbox, Webpack, JWT Authentication
- Git, Github, GitLab, Bash/Shell

Soft Skills

- Ability to work effectively with people with differing levels of technical knowledge.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team.
- Excellent judgment and integrity with the ability to make timely and sound decisions.
- Attention to details, perfectionism and a pixel-perfect eye.
- Ability to clearly communicate with a team, balance job obligations with other commitments, self-initiate and take responsibility for tasks.

Languages

- English
- Georgian